<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rishabh Chaudhary</title>
    <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rishabh Chaudhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) : 2018 | Rishabh Chaudhary</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 13:39:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rishabhchaudhary.in/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Story</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/love_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 13:39:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/love_story/</guid>
      <description>It all started with a pleasant smile,
which left its imprint for a while.
Then came the part of introduction,
which lasted longer the usual deduction.
Our meetings started getting long and cosy,
little did we know that it&amp;rsquo;s going to be rosy.
The realization of it being love wasn&amp;rsquo;t late,
and for us, it was quite an elate.
With all this being told, let&amp;rsquo;s see where it goes,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC - Initial phase and getting selected</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/gsoc_initial_phase_and_getting_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 13:50:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/gsoc_initial_phase_and_getting_selected/</guid>
      <description>Previous post - GSOC - Selecting the project and organization
Success is no accident. It is hard work, perseverance, learning, studying, sacrifice and most of all, love of what you are doing or learning to do. - Pele
Understanding the Project As I&amp;rsquo;ve already chosen my project (Read the previous post), It was time to know it better and work for it. So, I studied the details of the project form the organization wiki page and got an Idea of what this project is about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC - Selecting the project and organization</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/gsoc_selecting_the_project_and_organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 13:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/gsoc_selecting_the_project_and_organization/</guid>
      <description>On February 5 I started working towards GSOC 2018. I remember the date because my birthday is on 4th February and it was the day I decided that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be a part of GSOC 2018.
So, the first step in the process is the selection of a project/organization. Instead of selecting the organization I thought to go for a project of my interest, as in case of selecting an organization it is possible that the organization is doing something that interests us but their available projects don&amp;rsquo;t interests us much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See you soon</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/see_you_soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:23:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/see_you_soon/</guid>
      <description> This Poem is dedicated to my dearest friend Pooja.
 See you soon,
even if that means passing through dunes.
You are one of my dearest friends,
for whom I pray, her happiness ascends.
You are one of the finest persons in my life,
whom I never want to see in strife.
You are the one inspiring girl,
who one day will surely shine like a pearl.

© : Rishabh Chaudhary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code(GSOC) 2018</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/rishabh_gsoc_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 10:51:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/rishabh_gsoc_2018/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code (GSOC) 2018 result was announced on April 23 at 09:30PM. I got selected for GSOC 2018 😊 in organization The Libreswan Project. My project is Web based Certificate and Profile User Interface.
I am really happy 😊, It means a lot to me. Special thanks to Manoj Kumar, Gurpreet singh and Lokesh sharma. These guys helped me a lot in making this possible by motivating and supporting me during the phase, also my family and friends who always encouraged me to go an extra mile and helped me in my bad times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am not</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/i_am_not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 19:55:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/i_am_not/</guid>
      <description>I am not a good listener,
but want to listen to you for hours.
I am not humorous,
but want to make you laugh.
I am not good at time management,
but want to spend time with you.
I am not intelligent,
but want to solve complex problems, with you.
I am not good at expressing feelings,
but still want to share them with you.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful flowers</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/beautiful_flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 12:24:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/beautiful_flowers/</guid>
      <description> Thousands of beautiful flowers,
still can&amp;rsquo;t overcome my scars.
New opportunities everyday,
but can&amp;rsquo;t forget the lost fray.
Going off with a beautiful smile,
but who knows about the sorrows pile.
Love to see the happiness around,
but is somehow limited by bounds.
Still hopeful what the life may bring,
let me break the tied strings.

© : Rishabh Chaudhary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few things about WannaCry ransomware</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:24:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</guid>
      <description>A global cyber attack has been underway since Friday 12 May 2017, affecting more than 200,000 organizations and 230,000 computers in over 150 countries. It has been described as unprecedented in scale.

Well It’s source code is not yet available, but below is some information that can be useful in understanding its structure and behavior.
 Virus Name: WannaCrypt, WannaCry, WanaCrypt0r, WCrypt, WCRY Vector: All Windows versions before Windows 10 are vulnerable if not patched for MS-17–010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does ZeroNet Work?</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Asymmetric Cryptography  When i create a new site we get two keys -
Private Key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvL\ Vh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xu Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQ\ QPKT8tfjCNjEX9JM  a) Private key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvL
Vh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xIu
 Only I have it. It allows me to sign new content to the site. No central registry, it never leaves my computer. It don’t need to be published anywhere. Impossible to modify site without it.  b) Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is ZeroNet the future?</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</guid>
      <description>What is ZeroNet?
It’s a Decentralized web platform using Bitcoin cryptography and BitTorrent network. Which provides open, free &amp;amp; uncensorable websites.
 Why ZeroNet?
   Because it provides Peer-to-Peer connectivity without any central server and hence content is distributed directly to visitors. Uncensored because its nowhere to be found. No hosting cost as sites are served by visitors. Impossible to shutdown as its nowhere yet everywhere. No point of failure as the site will keep serving till the last peer serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Misunderstood</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/being-misunderstood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 22:29:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/being-misunderstood/</guid>
      <description>Being misunderstood has become a part of my life,
people here will judge you on the base of strife.
Life has changed a lot,
like a growing money-plant in a pot.
Once a happy soul,
is now a hated ghoul.
No, one wants to be in your shoes,
but everyone wants to get you blues.
Trying hard to find the meaning of life’s valley,
but at every step being cheated by some ally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team .EXE (joining the Team - part 1)</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</guid>
      <description>Its raining outside &amp;amp; i am writing this post , Hope it helps :-)
It was my 2nd year &amp;amp; SFD’s work was in progress &amp;amp; for that I’d been assigned a senior to work with &amp;amp; he was Arun Chaudhary (core coordinator of Team EXE) &amp;amp; believe me he was impressed with my work (what say Arun Sir? ;-) ) &amp;amp; he’d suggested me to join the team during nimbus(Tech fest of NIT Hamirpur) 2k16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A trip to Shillong (Part - 1) On the way to Shillong</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/a_trip_to_shillong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 11:17:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/a_trip_to_shillong/</guid>
      <description>Those were the summer vacations when everybody was experiencing boredom at its best. And i was also one of those and was thinking on “The ways to kill boredom?”, when i came to know that my family has already planned a trip out to Shillong and i wasn’t even informed about this trip (It was a surprise for me) and i really liked it (oh! sorry Loved it).
 How we reached there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make your computer welcome you</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 10:11:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</guid>
      <description>Open notepad by searching it in the menu.
 Copy these lines as it is and paste them into your notepad.
Dim speaks, speech speaks=&amp;quot;Welcome back USERNAME &amp;quot; Set speech=CreateObject(&amp;quot;sapi.spvoice&amp;quot;) speech.Speak speaks  Note — You can replace USERNAME with your Name/Username.
 Save the file as welcome.vbs (on your desktop) or any other name with extension as “.vbs”.
 Go to C drive the view option on the menu bar and check the option “Show hidden files”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended uses of VLC</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</guid>
      <description>You thought vlc as just another audio/video player, but to your surprise its much more than that. If you are using vlc you must be using it because its quite popular and maybe your friend recommended it to you as its a good player and if you ask him/her how its good then you must got in reply that it can play more formats of video than any other player can even think of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality &amp; its relation with free basics and internet.org by Facebook</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 11:25:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</guid>
      <description>This post deals with the importance of Net neutrality and its relation with services like free basics and internet.org by facebook.
 what is net neutrality?  Net neutrality (also network neutrality, Internet neutrality, or net equality) is the principle that Internet service providers and governments should treat all data on the Internet the same, not discriminating or charging differentially by user, content, site, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or mode of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girl I Loved</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/the-girl-i-loved/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 22:29:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/the-girl-i-loved/</guid>
      <description>The girl I loved the most,
Left me at the coast.
She said she don’t want to continue,
To which shocked, I said k… I don’t want to burden you.
She was happy I don’t know why,
But for me it was hard to cry.

 The coast grew silent &amp;amp; so did I,
But she was somehow smiling with joy,.
The happy moments come to my mind,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proposal Unaccepted</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/a-proposal-unaccepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 22:29:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/a-proposal-unaccepted/</guid>
      <description>Loving a girl was pretty fine,
As it gave me an experience like drinking wine.
She was like a princess and I was like a slave,
And falling for her may be leading me to my grave.
Even though I proposed her as I loved her a lot,
To which she even does not give a second thought.
She started ignoring me as like I am a rotten apple,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting my website - Journey to Github</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 09:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</guid>
      <description>After 12th when i got admission in NIT Hamirpur, I came across few seniors who’re just great, then i discovered that they all had their websites which represents them on this World wide web. As i had the knowledge of html learn’t in 10 class and was very much impressed by its abilities, i thought of designing a website of my own. Before this me along with my few friends had tried designing and hosting of two unsuccessful sites (Photo-effects and Cyberbullying — unsuccessful because we left the development of these sites in between and deleted them after few months) and so this was my 3rd experiment with hosting and developing a site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When I saw her for the first time</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/when-i-saw-her-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 22:29:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/when-i-saw-her-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>When I saw her for the first time,
She was wearing a white dress with a glittering shine.
She walked down the stairs with a flower in hand,
And eyes started rolling on her with an ovational stand.
She was a princess with a pleasant smile,
Which can even cure a wounded soldier in a while.
She was a perfect partner as I wanted,
but I can’t take her as for granted,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>