<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Rishabh Chaudhary</title>
    <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Rishabh Chaudhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) : 2018 | Rishabh Chaudhary</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:24:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rishabhchaudhary.in/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Few things about WannaCry ransomware</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:24:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</guid>
      <description>A global cyber attack has been underway since Friday 12 May 2017, affecting more than 200,000 organizations and 230,000 computers in over 150 countries. It has been described as unprecedented in scale.

Well It’s source code is not yet available, but below is some information that can be useful in understanding its structure and behavior.
 Virus Name: WannaCrypt, WannaCry, WanaCrypt0r, WCrypt, WCRY Vector: All Windows versions before Windows 10 are vulnerable if not patched for MS-17–010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does ZeroNet Work?</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Asymmetric Cryptography  When i create a new site we get two keys -
Private Key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvLVh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xu Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQQPKT8tfjCNjEX9JM  a) Private key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvLVh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xIu
 Only I have it. It allows me to sign new content to the site. No central registry, it never leaves my computer. It don’t need to be published anywhere. Impossible to modify site without it.  b) Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQQPKT8tfjCNjEX9JM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is ZeroNet the future?</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</guid>
      <description>What is ZeroNet?
It’s a Decentralized web platform using Bitcoin cryptography and BitTorrent network. Which provides open, free &amp;amp; uncensorable websites.
 Why ZeroNet?
   Because it provides Peer-to-Peer connectivity without any central server and hence content is distributed directly to visitors. Uncensored because its nowhere to be found. No hosting cost as sites are served by visitors. Impossible to shutdown as its nowhere yet everywhere. No point of failure as the site will keep serving till the last peer serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team .EXE (joining the Team - part 1)</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</guid>
      <description>Its raining outside &amp;amp; i am writing this post , Hope it helps :-)
It was my 2nd year &amp;amp; SFD’s work was in progress &amp;amp; for that I’d been assigned a senior to work with &amp;amp; he was Arun Chaudhary (core coordinator of Team EXE) &amp;amp; believe me he was impressed with my work (what say Arun Sir? ;-) ) &amp;amp; he’d suggested me to join the team during nimbus(Tech fest of NIT Hamirpur) 2k16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make your computer welcome you</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 10:11:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</guid>
      <description>Open notepad by searching it in the menu.
 Copy these lines as it is and paste them into your notepad.
Dim speaks, speech speaks=&amp;quot;Welcome back USERNAME &amp;quot; Set speech=CreateObject(&amp;quot;sapi.spvoice&amp;quot;) speech.Speak speaks  Note — You can replace USERNAME with your Name/Username.
 Save the file as welcome.vbs (on your desktop) or any other name with extension as “.vbs”.
 Go to C drive the view option on the menu bar and check the option “Show hidden files”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended uses of VLC</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</guid>
      <description>You thought vlc as just another audio/video player, but to your surprise its much more than that. If you are using vlc you must be using it because its quite popular and maybe your friend recommended it to you as its a good player and if you ask him/her how its good then you must got in reply that it can play more formats of video than any other player can even think of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality &amp; its relation with free basics and internet.org by Facebook</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 11:25:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</guid>
      <description>This post deals with the importance of Net neutrality and its relation with services like free basics and internet.org by facebook.
 what is net neutrality?  Net neutrality (also network neutrality, Internet neutrality, or net equality) is the principle that Internet service providers and governments should treat all data on the Internet the same, not discriminating or charging differentially by user, content, site, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or mode of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting my website - Journey to Github</title>
      <link>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 09:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh Chaudhary)</author>
      <guid>https://rishabhchaudhary.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</guid>
      <description>After 12th when i got admission in NIT Hamirpur, I came across few seniors who’re just great, then i discovered that they all had their websites which represents them on this World wide web. As i had the knowledge of html learn’t in 10 class and was very much impressed by its abilities, i thought of designing a website of my own. Before this me along with my few friends had tried designing and hosting of two unsuccessful sites (Photo-effects and Cyberbullying — unsuccessful because we left the development of these sites in between and deleted them after few months) and so this was my 3rd experiment with hosting and developing a site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>