<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Rishabh&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://therishabh.in/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Rishabh&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) : 2019 | Rishabh</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 22:04:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://therishabh.in/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginners Guide to Google Summer of Code (GSoC)</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/the_beginners_guide_to_google_summer_of_code_gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 22:04:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/the_beginners_guide_to_google_summer_of_code_gsoc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the beginners guide to Google Summer of Code (GSoC). The Google Summer of Code is an annual global program sponsored and managed by Google. The program focuses on bringing more student developers into open source project development. In this program, the students work with an Open source organization under the guidance of mentors (selected organization members) on a 3-month programming project in Summers.
Table of Contents  What is Open Source  Why Should we Care How to make a contribution Difference between Open Source, Freeware and Other Softwares  What is git and GitHub  Version control systems  What is Google Summer of Code  Eligibility criteria Am I good Enough Benefits of GSoC Required Skills  How to Start  Selecting the Project and Organization Understanding the Project Drafting the Project Proposal Getting Selected  Terminologies  What is Open Source The term Open Source means the source code of the software is freely available to its users and anyone can modify it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Completing the project</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_completing_the_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 11:30:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_completing_the_project/</guid>
      <description>Previous post - GSoC - Initial phase and getting selected
First Evaluation I was very excited at the beginning of the project, as it is a whole new experience, especially for a student. So, I started working on the project in May. The starting was challenging as I choose Django as the framework which the project is going to be built on, I did so because it was most suitable as per the requirements of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Initial phase and getting selected</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_initial_phase_and_getting_selected/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 13:50:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_initial_phase_and_getting_selected/</guid>
      <description>Previous post - GSoC - Selecting the project and organization
Success is no accident. It is hard work, perseverance, learning, studying, sacrifice and most of all, love of what you are doing or learning to do. - Pele
Understanding the Project As I&amp;rsquo;ve already chosen my project (Read the previous post), It was time to know it better and work for it. So, I studied the details of the project form the organization wiki page and got an Idea of what this project is about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Selecting the project and organization</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_selecting_the_project_and_organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 13:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/gsoc_selecting_the_project_and_organization/</guid>
      <description>I started working towards GSoC 2018 in the first week of February. I remember because my birthday is in February and it was then I decided that I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be a part of GSoC 2018.
So, the first step in the process is the selection of a project/organization. Instead of selecting the organization I thought to go for a project of my interest, as in case of selecting an organization it is possible that the organization is doing something that interests us but their available projects don&amp;rsquo;t interest us much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Summer of Code(GSoC) 2018</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/rishabh_gsoc_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 10:51:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/rishabh_gsoc_2018/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2018 result was announced on April 23 at 09:30 PM. I got selected for GSoC 2018 😊 in the organization The Libreswan Project. My project is Web based Certificate and Profile User Interface.
I am really happy 😊, It means a lot to me. Special thanks to Manoj Kumar, Gurpreet Singh and Lokesh sharma. These guys helped me a lot in making this possible by motivating and supporting me during the phase, also my family and friends who always encouraged me to go an extra mile and helped me in my bad times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few things about WannaCry ransomware</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 12:24:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/few_things_about_wannacry_ransomware/</guid>
      <description>A global cyber attack has been underway since Friday 12 May 2017, affecting more than 200,000 organizations and 230,000 computers in over 150 countries. It has been described as unprecedented in scale.
Well It’s source code is not yet available, but below is some information that can be useful in understanding its structure and behavior.
 Virus Name: WannaCrypt, WannaCry, WanaCrypt0r, WCrypt, WCRY Vector: All Windows versions before Windows 10 are vulnerable if not patched for MS-17–010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does ZeroNet Work?</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/how_does_zeronet_work/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Asymmetric Cryptography  When i create a new site we get two keys -
Private Key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvL\ Vh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xu Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQ\ QPKT8tfjCNjEX9JM  a) Private key 5JNiiGspzqt8sC8FM54FMr53U9XvL
Vh8Waz6YYDK69gG6hso9xIu
 Only I have it. It allows me to sign new content to the site. No central registry, it never leaves my computer. It don’t need to be published anywhere. Impossible to modify site without it.  b) Public key 16YsjZK9nweXyy3vNQ</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is ZeroNet the future?</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/is_zeronet_the_future/</guid>
      <description>What is ZeroNet?
It’s a Decentralized web platform using Bitcoin cryptography and BitTorrent network. Which provides open, free &amp;amp; uncensorable websites.
 Why ZeroNet?
   Because it provides Peer-to-Peer connectivity without any central server and hence content is distributed directly to visitors. Uncensored because its nowhere to be found. No hosting cost as sites are served by visitors. Impossible to shutdown as its nowhere yet everywhere. No point of failure as the site will keep serving till the last peer serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team .EXE (joining the Team - part 1)</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 10:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/team_exe_joining_the_team/</guid>
      <description>Its raining outside &amp;amp; i am writing this post , Hope it helps :-)
It was my 2nd year &amp;amp; SFD’s work was in progress &amp;amp; for that I’d been assigned a senior to work with &amp;amp; he was Arun Chaudhary (core coordinator of Team EXE) &amp;amp; believe me he was impressed with my work (what say Arun Sir? ;-) ) &amp;amp; he’d suggested me to join the team during nimbus(Tech fest of NIT Hamirpur) 2k16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make your computer welcome you</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 10:11:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/how_to_make_your_computer_welcome_you/</guid>
      <description>Open notepad by searching it in the menu.
 Copy these lines as it is and paste them into your notepad.
Dim speaks, speech speaks=&amp;quot;Welcome back USERNAME &amp;quot; Set speech=CreateObject(&amp;quot;sapi.spvoice&amp;quot;) speech.Speak speaks  Note — You can replace USERNAME with your Name/Username.
 Save the file as welcome.vbs (on your desktop) or any other name with extension as “.vbs”.
 Go to C drive the view option on the menu bar and check the option “Show hidden files”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended uses of VLC</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:00:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/extended_uses_of_vlc/</guid>
      <description>You thought vlc as just another audio/video player, but to your surprise its much more than that. If you are using vlc you must be using it because its quite popular and maybe your friend recommended it to you as its a good player and if you ask him/her how its good then you must got in reply that it can play more formats of video than any other player can even think of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Neutrality &amp; its relation with free basics and internet.org by Facebook</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 11:25:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/net_neutrality_and_its_relation_with_free_basics_and_internet.org_by_facebook/</guid>
      <description>This post deals with the importance of Net neutrality and its relation with services like free basics and internet.org by facebook.
 what is net neutrality?  Net neutrality (also network neutrality, Internet neutrality, or net equality) is the principle that Internet service providers and governments should treat all data on the Internet the same, not discriminating or charging differentially by user, content, site, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or mode of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hosting my website - Journey to Github</title>
      <link>https://therishabh.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 09:41:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>rishabh0402@gmail.com (Rishabh)</author>
      <guid>https://therishabh.in/hosting_my_website_journey_to_github/</guid>
      <description>After 12th when i got admission in NIT Hamirpur, I came across few seniors who’re just great, then i discovered that they all had their websites which represents them on this World wide web. As i had the knowledge of html learn’t in 10 class and was very much impressed by its abilities, i thought of designing a website of my own. Before this me along with my few friends had tried designing and hosting of two unsuccessful sites (Photo-effects and Cyberbullying — unsuccessful because we left the development of these sites in between and deleted them after few months) and so this was my 3rd experiment with hosting and developing a site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>